# Jem WALKER

## Graduate student in translation and interpretation +1-720-548-0171 / jw7@middlebury.edu

Translation and interpretation student at the Middlebury Institute. Exploring possible specializations including legal translation, but eager for experience in a wide range of domains. Passionate about translation and interpretation. Outside of languages, experience in the political field. Developed negotiation skills working with stakeholders and constituents.

## **LANGUAGES**

## English

(native, UK and US variants)

## French

(full proficiency)

## Spanish

(passive)

#### **SKILLS**

- **Translation**
- Consecutive interpretation
- MT post-editing
- Proofreading
- Software
  - SDL Trados
  - MemoQ
  - Microsoft Office Suite
  - Adobe Creative Cloud
  - Front-end web design (eg HTML and CSS)
- Research and source analysis

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Office of the Governor of Colorado Intern

Denver, Colorado Sep-Nov 2018

- Helped communicate the Governor's vision by writing copy for the Governor's proclamations and correspondence with constituents
- Completed other creative and administrative tasks as required

Administrative assistant / Citizens' Advocate

Nov 2018-Jan 2019

- Continued responsibilities and projects from internship
- Frontline role, engaging with constituents and providing operational support

Scheduling assistant

Jan-Jun 2019

- Joined scheduling team in new administration
- Established processes to ensure that the Governor's time was optimally planned
- Connected with stakeholders to keep the day-to-day business of governance running smoothly

Académie de Clermont-Ferrand

Auvergne, France

English Assistant/Teacher

Oct 2016-Apr 2017

- Developed English-language conversation skills in students aged 11-21
- Responded dynamically to different students' levels of aptitude to help each student achieve maximum progress

**Elk Meadow Partners Recruitment** 

Evergreen, Colorado

Administrative assistant and webmaster

Aug-Sep 2015

- Data input
- Industry research
- Designed and coding a new website for the firm from scratch in order to extend its reach

#### **EDUCATION**

Middlebury Institute of International Studies

MA Translation and Interpretation (French-English)

Monterey, California

Seoul, South Korea

2019-present

University of Leeds

BA French and Politics (2:1 classification)

Leeds, England 2014-2018

**Korea University** 

International Summer Campus

2015

American Foreign Policy and Korean Language

## THANK YOU FOR YOUR CONSIDERATION

+1-720-548-0171 / jw7@middlebury.edu